<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nathaniel Saul | Around About</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nathaniel Saul | Around About</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Čech Complex Playground</title>
      <link>/blog/nerve-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nerve-playground/</guid>
      <description>--
Čech complexes are one of the main tools for building a simplicial complex from data and are used regularly for Persistent Homology. This post provides an interactive demonstration of the Čech complex for a 2-dimensional data set. It is meant to help newcomers gain an intuition about the complex.
Visualization The resulting simplicial complex is overlaid on top of the covers. Here we only calculate the nerve up to order 2, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/updates/visxai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/visxai/</guid>
      <description>My work on using Mapper to visualize machine learning models was accepted to IEEE Vis VISxAI Workshop!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/updates/scikit-tda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/scikit-tda/</guid>
      <description>Scikit-tda.org is live! More details about the project are coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explainable Machine Learning with Mapper</title>
      <link>/research/explainable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/explainable/</guid>
      <description>While visiting Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, I collaborated with Dustin L. Arendt to develop new ways Mapper could be applied for explaining machine learning models.
Initial progress in this direction will be a part of the IEEE VIS 2018 Workshop on VISxAI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sewing with Topology</title>
      <link>/research/stitching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/stitching/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with Bei Wang and Bala Krishnamoorthy, I am developing ways of composing Mappers built from different filter functions together, and developing techniques for quantifying the topological correlation and complexity inherent in particular filter functions.
I presented preliminary results of this work at the Young Researchers Forum at SoCG 2018. See the abstract here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/updates/socg-presented/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/socg-presented/</guid>
      <description>I presented my work on stitching mappers together at the Young Researchers Forum at the Symposium on Computational Geometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/updates/socg-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/socg-accepted/</guid>
      <description>My work abstract was accepted to the Symposium on Computational Geometry&amp;rsquo;s Young Researchers Forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/updates/research-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/research-showcase/</guid>
      <description>I won second place at the WSUV Research Showcase for my talk on exploring high-dimensional data with Mapper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/updates/nasa-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/nasa-grant/</guid>
      <description>I was awarded the NASA Space Grant Fellowship to apply TDA to classification of galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/updates/pnnl-internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/pnnl-internship/</guid>
      <description>I will be joining the Visual Analytics Group at Pacific Northwest National Laboratories as a Research Intern for the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerves and Towers I: Introduction</title>
      <link>/blog/towers-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/towers-basics/</guid>
      <description>In unsupervised learning, one of the main questions we want to answer is what type of structure does this set or shape have? The field of algebraic topology supplies a few tools to help answer this question. We can ask topological questions about the data, such as how many clusters or connected components are there? or are there gaps, holes, or voids in the data?. These question can be easy to answer if the shape is well defined, but in practice, we instead have data sampled from that shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerves and Towers II: Nerves</title>
      <link>/blog/towers-nerves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/towers-nerves/</guid>
      <description>The nerve is a simplicial complex built from a cover. It is a discrete summarization of the cover that captures the interesting topological features. Additionally, if the cover is sufficiently refined, then the nerve is guaranteed to preserve the topological features. A nerve of a cover is constructed in a very straight forward way: An (n-1)-dimensional simplex is added for each nonempty n-way intersection of elements of the cover.
The nerve of a cover \(~\mathcal{N}(\mathcal{U})\) is a set of simplices such that $$ \mathcal{N} (\mathcal{U}) = \left\{(j, \ldots, k) : \bigcap_{i = j, \ldots, k} U_i \right\}$$  The one-way intersection of a set is vacuously nonempty, so we add a vertex for every element of the cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerves and Towers III: Towers</title>
      <link>/blog/towers-towers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/towers-towers/</guid>
      <description>Once we understand the tower, we will show that it plays nice with all of the other definitions we have constructed so far and how it allows us to naturally define a multiscale mapper.
A tower \(~\mathcal{T} \) is a tuple ( \(T_\epsilon\), \(\{t_{\epsilon, \epsilon^\prime}\}\)) of indexed objects \( T_\epsilon \) with morphisms \[t_{\epsilon, \epsilon^\prime}: T_\epsilon \to T_{\epsilon^\prime} \] defined when \( \epsilon \le \epsilon^\prime \). Additionally, we must have that morphisms are composable, that is \( t_{\epsilon, \epsilon^\prime} \circ t_{\epsilon^\prime, \epsilon^{\prime \prime}} = t_{\epsilon, \epsilon^{\prime \prime}} \).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Mapper?</title>
      <link>/blog/mapper-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mapper-intro/</guid>
      <description>As one of the main tools from the field of Topological Data Analysis, Mapper has been shown to be particularly useful for exploring high dimensional point cloud data. This post will walk through the mapper construction from an intuitive perspective and demonstrate how it can be constructed on a toy example.
Motivation Mapper is way to construct a graph (or simplicial complex) from data in a way that reveals the some of the topological features of the space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An argument for TDD</title>
      <link>/blog/debug-driven-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/debug-driven-development/</guid>
      <description>In this post, We propose a new software development methodology dubbed debug-driven development. Building upon work out of context and ignoring basic principles of time management, our proposed method cuts the average development* time of a project in half.
By using test driven development, we can redefine the develop-debug process to completely eliminate the development step. Instead of developing a feature, we can fix a broken test and in doing so the development portion of the develop-debug process disappears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/updates/passed-gqe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/passed-gqe/</guid>
      <description>I passed my Graduate Qualifying Exams!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy classification</title>
      <link>/research/galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/galaxies/</guid>
      <description>I was awarded a NASA space grant through WSU to develop methods using Topological Data Analysis for classifying galaxies that have WR-bumps or not.
Check out my blog post Classification using Persistence Images for a walk through on the methods I used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kepler Mapper</title>
      <link>/software/kepler-mapper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/kepler-mapper/</guid>
      <description>I actively maintain Kepler Mapper, a popular Python library for creating and visualizing Mappers. We provide a scikit-learn style API that is intuitive and approachable for data scientists and machine learning researchers. Check out the documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persim</title>
      <link>/software/persim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/persim/</guid>
      <description>I developed Persim, a library for computing persistence images of persistence diagrams. To learn more, check out the documentation page or see the source on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ripser.py</title>
      <link>/software/ripser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/ripser/</guid>
      <description>Along with Christopher Tralie, I help maintain the Python wrapper for Ripser, a blazingly fast c++ project originally developed by Ulrich Bauer.
My contribution have been user focused, spending most of my time on building an intuitive Python interface, visualization functionality, deployment and packaging, and automated testing and continuous integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TaDAsets</title>
      <link>/software/tadasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/tadasets/</guid>
      <description>TaDAsets is a project intended to provide easy to use data sets for demonstrating and exploring analytics techniques. The goal is to provide constructors for many common topological objects. Check out the documentation or the source code on github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Law of Demeter</title>
      <link>/blog/law-of-demeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/law-of-demeter/</guid>
      <description>The Law of Demeter is a small set of rules for how objects should interact with each other. It helps define the boundaries between objects and determine who controls and owns what. Applying this design principle gives each object their own personal space and keeps objects from micromanaging others.
The rules The LoD provides actionable and quantifiable rules for structuring software that help enable the SOLID principles. It defines what methods and variables an object is allowed to call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/tda_explanations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tda_explanations/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Explanations with Topological Data Analysis code{white-space: pre-wrap;} span.smallcaps{font-variant: small-caps;} span.underline{text-decoration: underline;} div.column{display: inline-block; vertical-align: top; width: 50%;}  html { font-size: 100%; overflow-y: scroll; -webkit-text-size-adjust: 100%; -ms-text-size-adjust: 100%; } .column { float: left; width: 50%; } .row:after { content: &#34;&#34;; display: table; clear: both; } body { color: #444; font-family: Georgia, Palatino, &#39;Palatino Linotype&#39;, Times, &#39;Times New Roman&#39;, serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 1.7; padding: 1em; margin: auto; max-width: 42em; background: #fefefe; } a { color: #0645ad; text-decoration: none; } a:visited { color: #0b0080; } a:hover { color: #06e; } a:active { color: #faa700; } a:focus { outline: thin dotted; } *::-moz-selection { background: rgba(255, 255, 0, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/tda_explanations.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tda_explanations.html/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>