<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source Software on Nathaniel Saul | Around About</title>
    <link>/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source Software on Nathaniel Saul | Around About</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kepler Mapper</title>
      <link>/software/kepler-mapper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/kepler-mapper/</guid>
      <description>I actively maintain Kepler Mapper, a popular Python library for creating and visualizing Mappers. We provide a scikit-learn style API that is intuitive and approachable for data scientists and machine learning researchers. Check out the documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persim</title>
      <link>/software/persim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/persim/</guid>
      <description>I developed Persim, a library for computing persistence images of persistence diagrams. To learn more, check out the documentation page or see the source on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ripser.py</title>
      <link>/software/ripser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/ripser/</guid>
      <description>Along with Christopher Tralie, I help maintain the Python wrapper for Ripser, a blazingly fast c++ project originally developed by Ulrich Bauer.
My contribution have been user focused, spending most of my time on building an intuitive Python interface, visualization functionality, deployment and packaging, and automated testing and continuous integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TaDAsets</title>
      <link>/software/tadasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/tadasets/</guid>
      <description>TaDAsets is a project intended to provide easy to use data sets for demonstrating and exploring analytics techniques. The goal is to provide constructors for many common topological objects. Check out the documentation or the source code on github</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>